A Guide to the Charles Olson Research Collection 1969.0001
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series I: Works, undated, 1927-1969
  - E. Unpublished poems
    - The wall the ass-hole - and the Seamless Tower... Manuscript. 1p., October 18, 1964. (Box 24, Folder 1175)
    - Mother... Photocopy. 4p., October 18, 1964. (Box 24, Folder 1176)
    - 1965-1969 (Box 25)
    - He took his job... Manuscript. 1p., ca. 1965-1968. (Box 25, Folder 1177)
    - The Wimple. Typescript. 1p., April 1, 1965. (Box 25, Folder 1178)
    - My Goddess. Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., April 16, 1965. (Box 25, Folder 1179)
    - Lovers. Typescript/Photocopy. 3p., May 29, 1965. (Box 25, Folder 1180)
    - The whole of Italy shall slip... Manuscript. 2p., ca. July 1965. (Box 25, Folder 1181)
    - Dancing Ganesha... Manuscript. 1p., ca. July 1965. (Box 25, Folder 1182)
    - Bull's eye out my window... Manuscript. 1p., July 1965. (Box 25, Folder 1183)
    - I'm serious now in wonder and in awe... Manuscript. 22p. Written on "Synapse 4, San Francisco '65.", July 26-28, 1965. (Box 25, Folder 1184)
    - Huge adulterous City, blood red Earth... Manuscript. 4p., August 13, 1965. (Box 25, Folder 1185)
    - You can't live according to those things... Manuscript. 1p., August 17, 1965. (Box 25, Folder 1186)
    - The Beloved - to be alive at all follow into the colors of her dress up... Manuscript. 4p., October 6, 1965. (Box 25, Folder 1187)
    - "Like a picture" the error of all promoted feeling... Manuscript. 9p., October 25, 1965. (Box 25, Folder 1188)
    - Magnificante. Typescript. 4p., November 26, 1965. (Box 25, Folder 1189)
    - The provocation of the sight of many things... Typescript. 3p., December 1, 1965. (Box 25, Folder 1190)
    - Come in the evening to fix my father's uniform... Manuscript. 3p., 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1191)
    - Otherwise one contributes to the contest instead of any change... Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., ca. 1966-1968. (Box 25, Folder 1192)
    - Traditionary knowledge and experience versus... Manuscript. 3p., ca. 1966-1968. (Box 25, Folder 1193)
    - Heaven. And Earth. Or Earth. And Heaven, no room... Manuscript. 1p., ca. 1966-1968. (Box 25, Folder 1194)
    - The dogs, in the early morn, are family... Manuscript. 1p., ca. 1966-1968. (Box 25, Folder 1195)
    - Mending my life, binding it into one life... Manuscript. 3p., ca. 1966-1968. (Box 25, Folder 1196)
    - Silver Sloon, and folder Brother Apollo... Manuscript. 3p., ca. 1966-1968. (Box 25, Folder 1197)
    - And there they were, inscribing a stone in runes... Manuscript. 1p., ca. 1966-1968. (Box 25, Folder 1198)
    - Doesn't tell doesn't hide marks by a sign... Manuscript. 2p., ca. 1966-1968. (Box 25, Folder 1199)
    - Blow hard and show off... Manuscript. 4p., ca. 1966-1968. (Box 25, Folder 1200)
    - Her genitals had catched by her left leg... Manuscript. 3p., ca. 1966-1968. (Box 25, Folder 1201)
    - To be able to see the product of the children... Manuscript. 1p., ca. 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1202)
    - An Address to the Nation and to Men. Manuscript. 5p., ca. 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1203)
    - Having or showing Hera? Manuscript. 5p., January 2, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1204)
    - Monet my bonnet (to whom I tie my mains'). Manuscript. 1p., January 18, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1205)
    - Monet my mains' to whom I tie my bonnet. Manuscript. 1p., January 18, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1206)
    - Father, painter... Manuscript. 1p., January 21, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1207)
    - I had to try to win my soul. Manuscript. 1p., February 9, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1208)
    - The Garden, Al Chimiya. Manuscript. 1p., February 14, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1209)
    - Blue now, all blue... Manuscript. 1p., February 16, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1210)
    - She lay with Pluto in the grain... Manuscript. 1p., ca. March 26, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1211)
    - As youth and woman and myself the Judges will strip me... Manuscript. 8p., March 26, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1212)
    - In the Early Morning, April Fool's Day 1966 - full tide too. Manuscript. 4p., April 1, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1213)
    - If it hadn't been for the [legworn Dancer?]... Manuscript. 1p., ca. April 27, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1214)
    - For things are perfected by their like and therefore the operator must himself participate in the work... Manuscript/Typescript. 4p., ca. May - October 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1215)
    - 1604, they will obey God, meaning we and 1629 Charles simply stopped them... Manuscript. 1p., May 30, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1216)
    - The far edge, of the continent... Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., ca. June 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1217)
    - On three sides ocean and, cutting its land connection... Manuscript. 8p., June 8, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1218)
    - 'Ode'. Manuscript. 1p. Written on verso of "Symptom," April 1966., June 13, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1219)
    - Procreation and Creation. Typescript. 1p., June 16, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1220)
    - For it was nearer this withdrawal than the boy had reached... Manuscript. 1p., June 17-18, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1221)
    - The seas air brought on the evening's own... Photocopy. 1p. Original in notebook "Record"., July 15, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1222)
    - The farther try me to get his day 11er - when I am about to marry? Manuscript. 1p., July 19, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1223)
    - There was a big fog on the mountain... Photocopy. 1p. Original in notebook "Record"., August 8, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1224)
    - And across the pelvis runs of perforated animal teeth... Manuscript. Written on booklet "From Salisbury Plain to South Siberia," by Stuart Piggott., ca. August 17, 1966. (Box 25, Folder 1225)
    - 474 - Eternal Youth as ideal. Manuscript. 2p., ca. 1967-1968. (Box 25, Folder 1226)
    - My Heart and Soul for Heaven. Manuscript. 1p., ca. 1967. (Box 25, Folder 1227)
    - Leave off the weeping and lamentation... Manuscript. 1p., February 4, 1967. (Box 25, Folder 1228)
    - The garishness, of the New Gloucester... Manuscript. 3p., October 5, 1967. (Box 25, Folder 1229)
    - Conceived of Easter and home at Christmas... Manuscript. 1p., February 1968. (Box 25, Folder 1230)
    - So much amount. Manuscript. 1p., June 29, 1968. (Box 25, Folder 1231)
    - The world, which is the same for all, is an ever-living fire... Manuscript. 2p., ca. July 24, 1968. (Box 25, Folder 1232)
    - It was a fantastic hill... Photocopy. 3p., ca. August 20, 1968. (Box 25, Folder 1233)
    - From a conversation. Manuscript. 1p., January 1, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 1234)
    - My merganser whose lovely neck... Manuscript. 1p., January 27, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 1235)
    - How long all this 'existence' here... Manuscript. 2p., February 13, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 1236)
    - The Unceasing Anima Changes of Form. Photocopy. 2p., ca. June 1, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 1237)
    - As the City sleeps the Fort is awake... Manuscript. 1p., June 27, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 1238)
    - I can even walk along Cressy beach's edge... Manuscript. 1p., June 27, 1969. (Box 25, Folder 1239)
    - undated (Box 26)
    - Unidentified fragments., Undated. (Box 26:1240-26:1347)
    - undated (Box 27)
    - Unidentified fragments., Undated. (Box 27:1348-27:1465)
    - (Box 28)
    - Oversize 1949-1969. (Box 28:1466-28:1479)
  - F. Essays
    - A-C (Box 29)
      - The Act of Image. Prose No. 254. Typescript. 3p., 1953. (Box 29, Folder 1480)
      - Active Vision of the World. Prose No. 150. Typescript. 2p. April 1965. (Box 29, Folder 1481)
      - Added precisions on the "new" sciences. Prose No. 241. Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., ca. 1953. (Box 29, Folder 1482)
      - An additional note on Poetry/History as the possibility of a Long Poem. Prose No. 284. Typescript. 1p., 1961. (Box 29, Folder 1483)
      - The advantages of literacy is that words can be on the page. Prose No. 297. Typescript. 1p., December 9 1963. (Box 29, Folder 1484)
      - Again Eastward [essay on Melville]. Prose No. 176. Typescript/Photocopy. 3p., ca. 1939-1940. (Box 29, Folder 1485)
      - "Again, the Tyrrhenian, Pythagoras!" Prose No. 218. Typescript. 4p., 1949. (Box 29, Folder 1486)
      - "Again the sense the forms we have are conventions..." Prose No. 215. Typescript. 3p., ca. 1949. (Box 29, Folder 1487)
      - Al Gorman. Prose No. 165. Typescript. 4p., ca. 1930. (Box 29, Folder 1488)
      - The Animate versus the Mechanical, and Thought. Prose No. 314. Typescript. 4p., February 15 1969. (Box 29, Folder 1489)
      - The Area, and the Discipline of, Totality. Prose No. 243. Typescript/Photocopy. 38p., ca. 1953. (Box 29, Folder 1490)
      - Article, without title, for Proof. Prose No. 117. Typescript. 13p., undated (Box 29, Folder 1491)
      - As Aimed as His Poem Is. Prose No. 103. Typescript. 11p., 1956. (Box 29, Folder 1492)
      - The Attack, Now, in Painting and Writing. Prose No. 53. Typescript/Photocopy of typescript. 14p., 1952. (Box 29, Folder 1493)
      - Autobiographical note. Prose No. 302. Manuscript. 2p., August 12, 1964. (Box 29, Folder 1494)
      - The backward of my creation. Prose No. 182. Manuscript. 3p., August 1940. (Box 29, Folder 1495)
      - The Beginning of 3rd Inst. Prose No. 257. Manuscript/Typescript. 27p., February 1953. (Box 29, Folder 1496)
      - The Bezel. Prose No. 124. Typescript. 4p., January 1962. (Box 29, Folder 1497)
      - A bibliography on America for Ed Dorn. Prose No. 274. Typescript. 16p. CO's TS removed from Robert Duncan's January 9, 1963 letter., January 1955. (Box 29, Folder 1498)
      - [A biographical statement for "Twentieth Century Authors." Prose No. 233. Typescript/Carbon copy. 5p., November 1952. (Box 29, Folder 1499)
      - The Bird, Himself. Prose No. 268. Typescript. 8p., July 1954. (Box 29, Folder 1500)
      - The body is a house. Prose No. 83. Typescript. 5p., 1955. (Box 29, Folder 1501)
      - The Born Dancer. Prose No. 4. Carbon copy. 4p., 1951. (Box 29, Folder 1502)
      - The Break-Up. Prose No. 57. Typescript. 9p., ca. 1953-1955. (Box 29, Folder 1503)
      - Bridge-Work. Prose No. 290. Manuscript. 2p., March 14, 1961. (Box 29, Folder 1504)
      - [Brooks Adams notes.] Prose No. 305. Manuscript/Typescript. 11p. and notated pamphlet "Harvard Reading List in American History, September 1938," 6p., 1965. (Box 29, Folder 1505)
      - Cabeza de Vaca. Prose No. 17. Typescript. 6p., January 21, 1947. (Box 29, Folder 1506)
      - Cagli + I on Love. Prose No. 183. Manuscript. 13p., 1940. (Box 29, Folder 1507)
      - Call me Ishmael. Prose No. 185. Typescript. 3p., ca. 1945. (Box 29, Folder 1508)
      - Carefulness (of the flow of time). Prose 160. Typescript. 9p., September 1, 1968. (Box 29, Folder 1509)
      - The cave. Prose No. 255. Typescript. 26p., 1953. (Box 29, Folder 1510)
      - The Celts and Plato. Prose No. 70. Typescript. 5p., November 1953. (Box 29, Folder 1511)
      - The characters are all fiction... Prose No. 265. Typescript. 1p., 1954. (Box 29, Folder 1512)
      - Christ as the act of his own life... Prose No. 111. Typescript. 6p., November 1958. (Box 29, Folder 1513)
      - Civil War. Prose No. 276. Manuscript. 3p., August 23, 1955. (Box 29, Folder 1513a)
      - Civilization and the soul. Prose No. 113. Manuscript/Typescript/Photocopy. 9p. Also see Notebook "Gloucester - Spring 1959.", 1958. (Box 29, Folder 1514)
      - The concept of danger as voiced by Max Lemmer. Prose No. 174. Manuscript. 1p., March 15, 1939. (Box 29, Folder 1515)
      - The Corpse Cold Catholicism of America. Prose No. 301. Typescript. 1p., July 1964. (Box 29, Folder 1516)
      - The Creation of Massachusetts: An Outline of An Essay in History. Prose No. 107. Typescript. 2p., December 26, 1957. (Box 29, Folder 1517)
      - Creatively we are neolithic... Prose No. 204. Typescript. 1p., ca. 1948. (Box 29, Folder 1518)
      - Credo. Prose No. 30. Typescript. 3p., ca. May - December 1949. (Box 29, Folder 1519)
      - The Crisis of the Third Foot. Prose No. 79. Typescript. 5p. Also see CO to Layton, August 1, 1954., July 31, 1954. (Box 29, Folder 1520)
      - Cro-Magnon Notes. Prose No. 65. Typescript. 11p., 1953. (Box 29, Folder 1521)
      - Culture and Revolution. Prose No. 45. Typescript. 12p., ca. 1952. (Box 29, Folder 1522)
      - Culture - A Stab at its Present Shape... Prose No. 49. Typescript. 4p., February 20, 1952. (Box 29, Folder 1523)
      - CUPS, or Dance; and WOMAN, or Sculpture. Prose No. 259. Typescript. 15p., February 22, 1953. (Box 29, Folder 1524)
      - Cy Twombly. Prose No. 51. Photocopy/Carbon copy. 32p. Also see CO to Robert Creeley, January 31, 1952. (Box 29, Folder 1525)
    - D-G (Box 30)
      - D.H. Lawrence and the high temptation of the mind. Prose No. 32. Typescript. 4p., January 21-22, 1950. (Box 30, Folder 1526)
      - David young, David old. Prose No. 212. Typescript/Carbon copy. 36p., November 1948. (Box 30, Folder 1527)
      - Definitions by undoing. Prose No. 97. Typescript. 7p., 1956-1957. (Box 30, Folder 1528)
      - Demeter (essay). Prose No. 104. Typescript. 5p., 1956. (Box 30, Folder 1529)
      - Demeter (essay) another version. Prose No. 278. Typescript. 3p., 1956. (Box 30, Folder 1530)
      - Depriapo or notes for an historian of a suppressed religion. Prose No. 197. Typescript. 10p., April 1947. (Box 30, Folder 1531)
      - Disney ought to be the Aesop of our time. Prose No. 180. Typescript. 2p., ca. 1940. (Box 30, Folder 1532)
      - Distinction Malinowski has used. Prose No. 227. Carbon copy. 1p., June 1951. (Box 30, Folder 1533)
      - Dogmatic curriculum, non-optional. Prose No. 127. Photocopy. 1p., October 1962. (Box 30, Folder 1534)
      - Dostoevsky and the possessed. Prose No. 181. Typescript. 3p., March 1940. (Box 30, Folder 1535)
      - The double axis. Prose No. 59. Typescript. 2p., ca. 1953. (Box 30, Folder 1536)
      - A draft of a plan for the college. Prose No. 105. Typescript. 12p., September 1, 1956. (Box 30, Folder 1537)
      - Drama, theatre and cinema today. Prose No. 173. Manuscript. 1p., 1938-1939. (Box 30, Folder 1538)
      - The drawings of Cagli (essay). Prose No. 21. Manuscript/Typescript. 10p., 1948. (Box 30, Folder 1539)
      - The dryness, of "The Tempest." Prose No. 24. Carbon copy. 14p., 1948-1949. (Box 30, Folder 1540)
      - Ed Sanders' language. Prose No. 304. Manuscript. 1p., 1964. (Box 30, Folder 1541)
      - Edward Dahlberg's essay on Moby Dick review. Prose No. 121. Typescript. 4p., 1960. (Box 30, Folder 1542)
      - The end of interest in carbon molecules. Prose No. 123. Typescript. 1p., December 1961. (Box 30, Folder 1543)
      - Eric Havelock's Preface to Plato. Prose No. 300. Manuscript. 11p., February 12, 1964. (Box 30, Folder 1544)
      - The Escaped Cock. Prose No. 224. Typescript/Photocopy/Carbon copy. 11p., October 1950. (Box 30, Folder 1545)
      - Essay on Melville. Typescript., 1948. (Box 30, Folder 1556)
      - Essay on the matter of. Prose No. 161. Photocopy. 14p., September 1968. (Box 30, Folder 1557)
      - Experience itself and measurement. Prose No. 311. Manuscript. 10p., 1966. (Box 30, Folder 1558)
      - The fabulatory inherence. Prose No. 147. Typescript. 2p., 1964. (Box 30, Folder 1559)
      - Fate will control meaningless chance sort person love. Prose No. 149. Manuscript. 1 Notebook., March 1965. (Box 30, Folder 1560)
      - A first draft of a reading list in the new sciences of man. Prose No. 273. Typescript. 3p., May 6, 1955. (Box 30, Folder 1561)
      - First facts (notes). Prose No. 191. Typescript. 4p., ca. 1947. (Box 30, Folder 1562)
      - The fish weir. Prose No. 1. Carbon copy. 6p., 1931. (Box 30, Folder 1563)
      - Fluff. Prose No. 9. Manuscript. 3p., ca. November 1961. (Box 30, Folder 1564)
      - "Form, no more than means, is caused..." Prose No. 81. Typescript. 12p., 1954. (Box 30, Folder 1565)
      - Further part. Prose No. 154. Manuscript/Photocopy. 6p., November 1965. (Box 30, Folder 1566)
      - Gabriel on American national symbols. Prose No. 175. Typescript. 1p., April 1939. (Box 30, Folder 1567)
      - Genuine missing pieces in the "thought" of the west. Prose No. 110. Typescript. 2p., November 1958. (Box 30, Folder 1568)
      - Geocentric and circumferential. Prose No. 128. Transcript. 2p., ca. 1963. (Box 30, Folder 1569)
      - Giovanni diPaolo (1403-1483). Prose No. 205. Typescript. 1p., ca. 1948. (Box 30, Folder 1570)
      - "Go out. The world is larger than any of its places..." Prose No. 88. Typescript. 2p., ca. 1955-1958. (Box 30, Folder 1571)
      - Grammar a book. Prose No. 289. Manuscript/Typescript. 5p., March 11, 1961. (Box 30, Folder 1572)
      - Grandpa, goodbye. Prose No. 211. Typescript/Carbon copy. 37p., March 1948? or possibly January 1950 [see Olson's letter to F. Boldereff, 30 January 1950.] (Box 30, Folder 1573)
      - The great origins of European thought (note). Prose No. 310. Manuscript/Photocopy. 24p., 1966. (Box 30, Folder 1574)
    - H-K (Box 31)
      - He peopled his world with their giant characters. Prose No. 177. Typescript. 1p., ca. 1939-1940. (Box 31, Folder 1575)
      - He slept. Prose No. 200. Carbon copy. 24p., ca. 1948. (Box 31, Folder 1576)
      - He was a player [Shakespeare introduction]. Prose No. 69. Manuscript/Typescript. 5p., November 1954. (Box 31, Folder 1577)
      - Herman Melville and the Civil War. Prose No. 184. Typescript. 3p., ca. 1940. (Box 31, Folder 1578)
      - The Hinges of civilization to be put back on the door. Prose No. 292. Manuscript. 2p., December 7, 1961. (Box 31, Folder 1579)
      - History and selfconsciousness have won. Prose No. 157. Manuscript/Typescript. 2p., November 4, 1967. (Box 31, Folder 1580)
      - History tutorial. Prose No. 100. Photocopy. 3p., ca. 1956. (Box 31, Folder 1581)
      - "History" essay. Prose No. 48. Typescript/Photocopy. 23p. Two letters separated to correspondence: 1) Letter dated February 14, 1952 from CO to John Chamberlain and 2) Letter, dated March 5, 1952, from John Chamberlain to CO. Photocopies of letters in folder., February 15, 1952. (Box 31, Folder 1582)
      - Homer and Bible. Prose No. 279. Manuscript/Typescript. 19p., ca. 1957. (Box 31, Folder 1583)
      - A house built by Capt. John Sores, 1763. Prose No. 295. Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., April 1962. (Box 31, Folder 1584)
      - How to work everyday. Prose No. 43. Typescript. 1p., July 14, ca. 1952-1956. (Box 31, Folder 1585)
      - Human universe--II. Prose No. 119. Typescript. 1p., 196-? (Box 31, Folder 1586)
      - Human universe. Prose No. 232. Typescript. Written on "Origin IV: A Quarterly for the Creative, featuring New Foreign Poetry, Winter '51-'52.", 1952. (Box 31, Folder 1587)
      - Human universe: draft of an essay. Prose No. 229. Typescript/Carbon copy. 4p., 1951. (Box 31, Folder 1588)
      - I am engaged in rather a different work entirely... Prose No. 306. Typescript. 2p., 1965. (Box 31, Folder 1589)
      - I am not the first poet who happily find material... Prose No. 152. Manuscript. 14p., October 11, 1965. (Box 31, Folder 1590)
      - I had been a psilanthropist... Prose No. 277. Typescript. 2p., ca. 1956. (Box 31, Folder 1591)
      - I write to name Cabeza De Vaca... Prose No. 189. Typescript. 3p., ca. 1946. (Box 31, Folder 1592)
      - Ideas for series of lectures at Richman's Institute of Contemporary Art. Prose No. 23. Typescript. 2p., ca. 1948. (Box 31, Folder 1593)
      - Imago. Prose No. 196. Typescript. 2p., 1947. (Box 31, Folder 1594)
      - Immediate and preliminary statement for whatever use. Prose No. 162. Manuscript/Typescript. 8p., December 27, 1968. (Box 31, Folder 1595)
      - In Adullam's lair. Prose No. 178. Typescript. 21p. Fragile., 1939. (Box 31, Folder 1596)
      - Innocence and knowledge. Prose No. 95. Typescript. 2 versions. 3p., October 1955. (Box 31, Folder 1597)
      - Introduction to the Sutter-Marshall lease with the Yalesumney Indians for monopoly of the gold-bearing lands. Prose No. 210. Typescript/Drawing. 2p., January 5, 1948. (Box 31, Folder 1598)
      - It is impossible to concern oneself... Prose No. 58. Typescript. 1p. Fragile., ca. 1953. (Box 31, Folder 1599)
      - It's hard work... Prose No. 156. Manuscript. 2p., April 30, 1966. (Box 31, Folder 1600)
      - The job is the old one... Prose No. 190. Typescript. 1p., ca. 1946. (Box 31, Folder 1601)
      - Joyce, Pound, and W.B. Yeats. Prose No. 12. Typescript/Carbon copy. 6p., ca. 1940-1947. (Box 31, Folder 1602)
      - Judson Crews' The Anatomy of Proserpine. Prose No. 91. Manuscript/Typescript. 3p., February 1955. (Box 31, Folder 1603)
      - Katherine Litz dance concert: a review. Prose No. 236. Carbon copy. 7p., August 1952. (Box 31, Folder 1604)
    - L-M (Box 32)
      - Language, and mythology. Prose No. 261. Typescript. 6p., March 4, 1953. (Box 32, Folder 1605)
      - Language and theater. Prose No. 269. Typescript. 7p., 1954. (Box 32, Folder 1606)
      - Language and theatre. Prose No. 272. Typescript. 9p., 1954. (Box 32, Folder 1607)
      - Language is a thumb. Prose No. 109. Photocopy of notebook., ca. April 7, 1958. (Box 32, Folder 1608)
      - The Law. Prose No. 39. Typescript. 5p., October 1951. (Box 32, Folder 1609)
      - A Letter of petition to the Viking fund. Prose No. 38. Typescript. 23p., June 1951. (Box 32, Folder 1610)
      - The limit of Melville... Prose No. 108. Typescript. 2p., ca. 1958-1959. (Box 32, Folder 1611)
      - Literary criticism in Emerson (term paper). Prose No. 169. Typescript. 43p. Fragile., June 1932. (Box 32, Folder 1612)
      - Logography. Prose No. 286. Manuscript/Typescript. 1p., ca. October 31, 1959. (Box 32, Folder 1613)
      - Love is the life of the beloved. Prose No. 84. Typescript. 1p., 1955. (Box 32, Folder 1614)
      - Man as townsman... Prose No. 86. Typescript. 2p., 1955. (Box 32, Folder 1615)
      - A man's life is a continual allegory. Prose No. 136. Typescript. 4p., December 26-27, 1963. (Box 32, Folder 1616)
      - Man, by nature, is man. Prose No. 85. Typescript. 1p., 1955. (Box 32, Folder 1617)
      - Mason. Prose No. 166. Manuscript. 4p., ca. 1930. (Box 32, Folder 1618)
      - The materials and weights of Herman Melville. Prose No. 235. Typescript/Carbon copy. 30p., March-August 1952. (Box 32, Folder 1619)
      - Mayan Letters bibliography. Prose No. 251. Typescript. 4p., October 1953. (Box 32, Folder 1620)
      - Melville and Homer: notes vis-a-vis V. Berard. Prose No. 29. Typescript. 5p. Letter separated into correspondence, dated March 25, 1949, from Merton Sealts to CO., March 28, 1949. (Box 32, Folder 1621)
      - Melville book manuscript. Prose No. 179. Typescript. 2p., 1939-1940. (Box 32, Folder 1622)
      - Melville's reading. Prose No. 171. Manuscript. 4p., 1934. (Box 32, Folder 1623)
      - Me-mo to Stefan and John. Prose No. 237. Carbon copy. 2p., 1952. (Box 32, Folder 1624)
      - The Methodology is the Form. Prose No. 46. Typescript. 7p., 1952. (Box 32, Folder 1625)
      - Methodology note for Mary Fitton. Prose No. 242. Manuscript. 3p., ca. 1951-1953. (Box 32, Folder 1626)
      - More notes toward the proposition: Man is prospective. Prose No. 22. Typescript. 3p., ca. 1948. (Box 32, Folder 1627)
      - The morphology -- the structure. Prose No. 101. Manuscript/Typescript. 8p., ca. 1956. (Box 32, Folder 1628)
      - The mother acquires the definite sacrificial sublimity of a heroine. Prose No. 172. Typescript. 2p., ca. 1936-1939. (Box 32, Folder 1629)
      - Mouths Biting Empty Air. Prose No. 15. Typescript. 2p., October 27, 1946. (Box 32, Folder 1630)
      - Mr. Dantini and His Twelve Year Old. Prose No. 188. Typescript. 3p., ca. 1946. (Box 32, Folder 1631)
      - Mr. Meyer. Prose No. 208. Typescript. 13p., 1948. (Box 32, Folder 1632)
      - My faith is, It is possible to know what your are doing... Prose No. 55. Manuscript. 4p., November 5, 1952. (Box 32, Folder 1633)